Finding Aid for Louise Van Voorhis Armstrong papers, 1934-1948
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Louise Van Voorhis Armstrong papers 1934-1948
Armstrong, Louise Van Voorhis, 1885-1948.
1 linear foot.
85677 Aa 2
County relief administrator and author. Manuscript of her book, We Too Are The People, which relates her experiences in relief work; also correspondence, reviews of her books, comments on the election of 1940, and reports on the work of the Federal Emergency Relief Administration in Manistee County, Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Louise Armstrong in May 1940. Donor no. 1133.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Louise Van Voorhis Armstrong was born in Chicago on August 16, 1887. She graduated from the University of Michigan with B.A. (1909) and M.A. (1910) degrees. At the University, Van Voorhis was woman's editor of the Michigan Daily. After graduation, she married Harry W. Armstrong in 1911 and the two of them eventually made their home in Manistee, Michigan. Here she continued her writing, mainly plays, and involved herself in social service work. Her most famous work was We Too Are The People, written in 1938 and considered by many to be an authoritative text on depression conditions in the state and particularly in Manistee county where Armstrong served as administrator of emergency relief for three years. She died March 3, 1948.
The Armstrong collection includes the manuscript to her book We Too Are the People, correspondence mainly relating to the book, and other miscellaneous papers, notably reports on the work of the Federal Emergency Relief Administration in Manistee County, Michigan.
Subjects:
Depressions--1929--Michigan.; Manistee County (Mich.); New Deal, 1933-1939--Michigan.; Public welfare--Michigan.; United States. Federal Emergency Relief Administration.; Women social workers--Michigan--Manistee County.; Social workers--Michigan--Manistee County.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
African Americans--Michigan.; Bars.; Colonists.; Depressions.; Internal migration.; Migration, Internal.; Laborers.; Manistee (Mich.); Manistee County (Mich.); United States. Federal Emergency Relief Administration.; Woodcutting.; Work relief.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Manuscript of We Too Are the People
  (includes some slight, indicated changes from the published volume)
  - Chapter 1-The Country (Box 1)
  - Chapter 2-The Country During the Crisis (Box 1)
  - Chapter 3-Emergency Relief Begins (Box 1)
  - Chapter 4-Direct Relief and the Old Folks (Box 1)
  - Chapter 5-Men in Boots (Box 1)
  - Chapter 6-Work Programs and Community Reaction (Box 1)
  - Chapter 7-The Redskins (Box 1)
  - Chapter 8-"Government Food" and Allied Projects (Box 1)
  - Chapter 9-Our Big Business and Some Special Events (Box 1)
  - Chapter 10-Women and Creeds and Christmas Toys (Box 1)
  - Chapter 11-Wild Women (Box 1)
  - Chapter 12-The Little White Dove (Box 1)
  - Chapter 13-The Trolls (Box 1)
  - Chapter 14-Manhunt (Box 1)
  - Chapter 15-Young Citizens and Little Trees (Box 1)
  - Chapter 16-Conclusion (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - January-February 1938 (Box 1)
  - March 1938 (Box 1)
  - April-May 1938 (Box 1)
  - June 1938 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1938 (Box 1)
  - 1939 (Box 1)
  - January-April 1940 (Box 1)
  - May-December 1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1948 (Box 1)
- Other Papers
  - Article on Rural Problems in Michigan, undated (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning relief activities in Manistee County, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Clippings and Review of We Too Are the People, 10 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Photographs. (Box 1)
    (many of the phootos were used in an exhibit detailing relief work undertaken in Manistee County during the depression; also photographs of a group intending to emigrate from Michigan to Alaska)